

CONTACT

- +39 340 9310 562
- ★ federico.decillia@gmail.com
- **9** Via Porpora 14, Milan (IT)
- 8 live:federico.decillia
- federico.decillia.github.io

EDUCATION

M.S IN BUSINESS STATISTICS

University of Padova (2012 - 2014)

B.S IN BUSINESS STATISTICS

University of Padova (2008 - 2011)

LLP ERASMUS (BARCELONA)

University Pompeu Fabra (2012)

ICT HIGH-SCHOOL DIPLOMA

I.T.I. Severi, Padua (2003 - 2008)

EXPERTISE

| Python, R | •••• |
|------------------------|-------|
| Git | •••• |
| Office, GSuite, iWork | •••• |
| BI (Tableau, Spotfire) | •••• |
| Spark | •••• |
| SQL | •••• |
| SAS, SPSS | •••• |
| KNime | •••• |
| AWS, GCP | •••• |
| CI/CD | •••• |
| Airflow | •••• |
| Docker | •••00 |

FEDERICO DE CILLIA

Senior Data Scientist - R&D, Market analysis, Media

ABOUT ME

Senior Data Scientist specialized in Big-Data analytics, Machine Learning, Time Series modeling, Automation & RPA, BI & Data Visualization.

Demonstrated history of strong innovation attitude, leading the change of international Data Science organizations to new tools and methodologies.

Proven track record of leading strategic analytics projects, from ideation to production of ML pipelines, RPA automations & BI solutions, using programming languages (Python, R, Spark, SQL), Data Visualization tools (Spotfire, Google Data Studio, Tableau, SAS VA), locally & in-cloud (AWS, Google Cloud Platform), exploiting Agile & Software development tools (Git, CI/CD, Airflow, Docker).

EXPERIENCE

Senior Data Scientist, Nielsen | 09/2017 - present

Lead many international projects (with up to 10 people per project) to implement scalable, automated Machine Learning (Classification, Regression, Clustering, Time Series) in multiple countries. Direct exposure to management & clients presenting business insights & analyses. Chair of Italian Diversity & Inclusion Team

Data Scientist Consultant, Bip (@ Sky Italy) | 04/2016 - 09/2017
Developed and implemented a NLP Churn-Prediction project & Text-Mining analyses, used to improve Retention/Upselling/Downgrade Marketing strategies.

Data Science Business Consultant, Value Lab | 09/2015 - 04/2016

SAS Masterclass Big Data, SAS Institute | 06/2015 - 09/2015

Data Mining Junior, Bocconi Alumni Association | 02/2015 - 06/2015

Tutor for exchange students, University of Padua | 2012 - 2014

LANGUAGE SKILLS ATTITUDES & INTERESTS

Italian: Mother tongueDriver of Innovation, Leader of changeEnglish: Proficient (C1)Communicator with Storytelling skillSpanish: Upper-Intermediate (B2)D&I and Sustainability advocate

COURSES & CERTIFICATIONS

| Machine Learning Specialization, University of Washington | 01/2020 |
|---|---------|
| Deep Learning Specialization, Deeplearning.ai. on Coursera | 06/2019 |
| Complete Git & Github Masterclass, O'Reilly | 10/2018 |
| Data Science and ML with Python and Spark, O'Reilly | 06/2018 |
| Python for Data Science, University of California San Diego | 12/2017 |
| Intro & Intermediate Python for Data Science, Datacamp | 09/2017 |
| Text Mining and Analytics, University of Illinois | 05/2017 |
| ML for Data Science and Analytics, Columbia University | 01/2017 |
| Tackling the challenges of Big Data, MIT | 09/2016 |
| SAS Programming - Macro Language - SQL, SAS Institute | 09/2015 |